<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://keepaliveit.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://keepaliveit.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-13T16:20:35-05:00</updated><id>https://keepaliveit.co.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Keep-Alive I.T Services</title><subtitle>A flexible Jekyll theme for your blog or site with a minimalist aesthetic.</subtitle><author><name>Joel Murphy</name></author><entry><title type="html">A brief introduction to Keep-Alive I.T Services.</title><link href="https://keepaliveit.co.uk/news/keep-alive-it-introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A brief introduction to Keep-Alive I.T Services." /><published>2019-11-26T17:20:28-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-26T17:20:28-05:00</updated><id>https://keepaliveit.co.uk/news/keep-alive-it-introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://keepaliveit.co.uk/news/keep-alive-it-introduction/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hello-world-were-keep-alive-it-services&quot;&gt;Hello World, we’re Keep-Alive I.T Services!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a great honour for me to be able to write the very first official blog post for the Keep-Alive I.T Services website - after months of careful &amp;amp; detailed planning, writing, and testing; Alongside working a full-time day job to be able to fund establishing this new company, Keep-Alive I.T Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who is ‘me’? Good question. My name is &lt;a href=&quot;https://joel-murphy.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Joel Murphy&lt;/a&gt; and I am the founder of Keep-Alive I.T Services. I’ll be taking on the role of ‘Lead Consultant’ here within the company, whereby I’ll be working with clients to help them make strategic decisions to implement suitable technologies for their I.T related needs. I’ll also be  working on a significant amount of implementations for clients, in addition to working towards leading the company in a positive direction for the future. I forecast this to become somewhat of a hectic role as it has has kept me extremely occupied so far, and I honestly can’t wait to see what challenges it brings in the next coming months and years as I get to share my I.T expertise with the World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take analysing your existing I.T infrastructure and software processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take the time to write a brief introduction to Keep-Alive I.T explaining this new venture, our mission statement, and what the company hopes to bring myself and future clients in the medium-to-long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reasons-for-founding-keep-alive-it&quot;&gt;Reasons for founding Keep-Alive I.T&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I founded Keep-Alive I.T because I’ve worked in a range of different environments and seen some of the good and bad sides to different technology implementations at different organisations in both, Windows and Linux Operating System environments. Sure, not everyone gets things right first time but when you’re constantly seeing newbies (or people who think they’re experienced with something - when in reality they have absolutely no clue about) implementing old, dying technologies at a company just because they have a senior status without any redundancy or intention of scale, it makes you wonder if there’s any hope at all for running reliable systems in production. When you’re an employee at an organisation, you sort of learn to shut your mouth and go with whatever solution you’re told to work towards. Consulting on the other hand is a great opportunity to make use of the expert skills you’ve acquired after so many years working with different technologies and seeing them grow over time. With this in mind, it has motivated me to start a company consulting clients on Development and operations 
As someone who keeps up to date with the latest and greatest technolgies, focuses on best practises, and practises development and operational I.T procedures; I see myself as a strong candidate for ‘bridging the gap’ between business and I.T workers and help break down complex technical problems into a language that others can easily understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-came-up-with-the-company-name&quot;&gt;How I came up with the company name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a techy at heart, you may be aware of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Keep-Alive&quot;&gt;HTTP Keep-Alive Header&lt;/a&gt; which is present in most modern web-browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Keep alive is a method to allow the same tcp connection for HTTP conversation instead of opening a new one with each new request. More simply put, it is a communication between the web server and the web browser that says “you can grab more than just one file at a time”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;development-and-operations-support&quot;&gt;Development and Operations support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-procurement&quot;&gt;I.T Procurement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-base&quot;&gt;Our base&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our registered office is based in the heart of Caerphilly, just a stones throw away from Cardiff.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/welsh-ice.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joel Murphy</name></author><summary type="html">Hello World, we’re Keep-Alive I.T Services! It’s a great honour for me to be able to write the very first official blog post for the Keep-Alive I.T Services website - after months of careful &amp;amp; detailed planning, writing, and testing; Alongside working a full-time day job to be able to fund establishing this new company, Keep-Alive I.T Services.</summary></entry></feed>